Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5206-PR
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Membership Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also lawyers, government officials, and newspapers and magazines regarding union member issues such as employment, complaints against fellow union members, pensions, contract negotiations and terms, benefits, credit union, 1199 News, member deaths, dues, membership cards, resumes, resignations, and member recommendations.
- Membership Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with union members regarding complaints and conflicts, organizing, union constitution, employment, benefits, initiation fee, vacation, pension, salaries, and dues.
- Membership Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also other unions, government officials, hospitals and universities regarding union member issues such as employment, complaints and criticisms, elections, union constitution, thanks, death of members, human rights, membership, contract provisions, strikes, elections, pensions, scholarships and recommendations. Contains press releases written by president Davis. Contains telegrams and flyers.
- Membership Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also lawyers, the district attorney, and the NYS Human Rights division regarding union member issues such as police, employment, complaints against fellow union members, scholarships, classification, laws, politics, pensions, contract negotiations and terms, benefits, credit union, 1199 News, anti-Semitism, conduct, member deaths, dues, membership cards, organizing, AFL-CIO, resignations, and member recommendations. Contains flyers, photos, memorandum, conciliation agreement, poem, and telegram from Davis to a member's mother.
- Membership Correspondence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also the government officials (the mayor) regarding union member complaints, benefits, salary, membership cards, thanks, 1199 News, Credit Unions, illnesses, the Brotherhood Fund, contract negotiations, training, and politics (Jimmy Hoffa).
- Miscellaneous, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence with colleges and universities, lawyers, hospitals, government officials, unions, and non-profit organizations inviting Davis to attend conferences, dinners, banquets, etc., asking him to speak at events, and thanking him for speaking or attending. Contains telegram from Governor Rockefeller inviting Davis to dinner. Contains draft of a speech, brochures, invitations, memorandums, flyers, and hand written notes.
- Correspondence-New Jersey, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with various New Jersey Labor Organizations in regards to events and support. Contains invitations and donation receipts.
- Correspondence-NYC Central Labor Council, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Contains telegrams, form letters and correspondence with NYC Central Labor Council regarding meetings, elections, current events, rallies, strikes, resolutions, civil rights, committees, and conflicts with 1199.
- Correspondence-Organizations, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Contains telegrams, handwritten notes, flyers, brochures, memorandums, form letters, bulletins, receipts, and correspondence from many organizations including the NAACP, Jewish Labor Committee, colleges and universities, lawyers, American's for Democratic Action, League of Women Voters, and many more. The majority of the communication is in regards to current events, meeting and dinner invitations, honorary memberships, donations, and conferences. Contains a telegram from Davis to President Lyndon B. Johnson regarding the protection of Martin Luther King Junior.
- Correspondence-Organizations, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Contains form letters from New School, American Committee for Democracy and Freedom In Greece, United Federation of Teachers, and the Rank and File Committee regarding current events, and financial contributions. Contains correspondence via letters and telegrams with the Japan Council against Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs, and GHI regarding invitations to a Conference and a Forum. Contains announcement from League of Women Voters. Contains project proposal from the Black and Puerto Rican Student Community of City College. Contains telegrams from Davis to Mayor Lindsay and Board of Education regarding President of United Federation of Teachers.
- Correspondence-Organizations, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with IUE and other unions in regards to the Strike with General Electric and the Local 1707 Strike. Contains correspondence with other unions and local groups in regards to conference invitations and monetary donations. Contains correspondence with various unions asking for copies of their constitutions. Contains CLASC News, 420 News Bulletin, A. Phillip Randolph pamphlet, a copy of the Local 144 Settlement, and "The Disaffiliation of the UAW" pamphlet.
- Correspondence-Organizations, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence and form letters from various political groups, civil rights groups, unions, health organizations, government organizations, and colleges and universities regarding conferences, monetary support, requests for information, the employment of ex-inmates, forming a new college, rallies, the Young Lords, Black Solidarity and the Vietnam War.
- Correspondence-Organizations, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence and flyers regarding conferences, Local 1199 as a Harvard Business Review case study, monetary support of a Child Development Center, and a pharmaceutical program.
- Correspondence-Sidney Von Luther, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and Von Luther, news paper articles and press releases, and Local 1199 Executive Council meeting minutes regarding the election of Sidney Von Luther as Senator, his consequent leave of absence from 1199, and his eventual permanent leave and severance pay from 1199.
- Correspondence-Unions, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with unions, non-profit organizations, the National Labor Relations Board, the Mayor, and the State of New York regarding employment, employment conditions, training, strikes (grape growers and teachers), requests for information, monetary contributions, dinner and funeral invitations, laws and bills, elections, conventions, rallies, and advertisements. Also includes telegrams, invitations, a news clipping, flyers and handwritten notes.
- Correspondence-Unions, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with unions, students, the mayor, James Hoffa, and non-profit organizations regarding invitations, organizing workers, strikes, congratulations, collective bargaining contracts, thanks, working conditions, elections, monetary donations, advice, and injunctions. Contains newsletters, handwritten notes, a news clipping, telegrams, a pamphlet, a leaflet, a statement, a sample membership survey (ILWU), and a policy statement on the jailing of James Hoffa.
- Correspondence-Unions, 1963-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with unions, universities, government organizations, non-profit organizations, lawyers, and the NLRB regarding requests for information, thanks, sympathy, conferences, strikes, invitations, federal employees, advice, conventions, collective bargaining, monetary contributions, Local 144, advertisements, Vietnam War, education policy, and loans. Contains AFL-CIO proceedings, telegram from Davis to president Nixon, pamphlet, memorandums, statements, news clippings, form letters, press release, speech, pension information, court invitation, and a legal service plan.
- Correspondence-Unions, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers, unions, government organizations and non-profit organizations regarding boycotts, thanks, negotiations, the pay board, Local 77, and 1199 News. Contains an agreement between Local 144 and Local 1199, UAW financial reports, handwritten notes, news clippings, SEIU resolutions, SEIU amendments to the constitution, and SEIU officer reports.
- Credit Union, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Contains information about Local 1199's credit union including monthly credit union statements, annual reports, and treasurer reports.
- Leon J. Davis-Lectures, Seminars, Articles, etc., 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Contains Davis' correspondence of a personal nature with hospitals, lawyers, accountants, and friends regarding travel, thanks, taxes, his father's health, and his daughter's employment during college. Contains letters from union members wishing him a speedy recovery from the hospital, as well as a letter from Davis in the hospital to a friend Max Steinbeck. Contains correspondence with unions, union members, non-profit organizations, colleges and universities, and lawyers regarding monetary donations, workman's compensation, meeting requests, invitations to speak at events, honors received by Davis, 1199 News, requests for information, and research studies. Contains transcript of Davis on a CBS television show. Contains reports, speeches, handwritten notes, and a biography of Davis from a calendar.
- Leon J. Davis-Memorandums, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings, member attendance, strikes, picketing and union policies and issues. Contains a copy of the 1199 Benefits Plan brochure, a meeting flyer, financial statements and car rental forms.
- Leon J. Davis-Memorandums, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings, member attendance, strikes, picketing, boycotts and union policies and issues. Contains a meeting agenda and form letters about meetings.
- Leon J. Davis-Memorandums, 1964-1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings and events, notifications, training classes, elections, member attendance, strikes, picketing, boycotts and union policies and issues. Contains a copy of a letter, a hiring request form, a contribution form, a petition, news clippings, and a copy of a publication--" The Modern Hospital."
- Leon J. Davis-Personal, 1943-1951 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with Bill Anderson, an 1199 officer who is stationed in the Pacific during WWII. Contains correspondence with companies, union members, friends, banks, and government departments regarding personal matters such as mortgage payments, the Taft-Hartley Act, a book club, stolen items, a bounced check, a broken pen, magazine subscriptions, advice, home insurance, and buying a new car. Contains a post card, a greeting card, a court summons, a picture, and a resolution.
- Leon J. Davis-Personal, 1964-1968 (Box 10, Folder 1a)
  Contains correspondence with government organizations, companies, accountants, lawyers, artists, friends, college professors, etc. regarding personal matters such as stolen credit cards, driver's license renewal, pictures, a pet, daughter's wedding, buying a brownstone home, and awards among other things. Contains individual income tax reports for Davis' daughter and himself and his wife, workers' compensation forms, a telegram, greeting cards, a letter to the New York Times, and a biographical sketch of Davis.
- Leon J. Davis-Personal, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with hospitals, friends, union members, a man he got into an accident with, artisans, banks, oil companies, the American Embassy in China, and the Peking Violations Bureau regarding personal matters such as a car accident, a parking violation, guest from Sweden, a mug, bills, credit cards, visit to China, and an invitation. Contains an accident report, and a biographical sketch of Davis.
- Leon J. Davis-Personal, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with the Department of Consumer Affairs, union members, a hotel, and family of union members regarding personal matter such as a memorial service, a credit card bill, complaints, and directions to a party. Contains auto mobile accident reports, a jewelry receipt, a subpoena, and an insurance form.
- Leon J. Davis-Personal, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with senators, congressmen, lawyers, the house of representatives, the New York Post, and community organizations regarding the deportation of Stoyan Pavesic. Contains handwritten notes, a telegram, and a news clipping about Stoyan Pavesic.
- Leon J. Davis-Reports, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Contains a report to membership on current union issues (Taft-Hartley Act and Liggett and Whelan strikes), a report on Local 1199 discussing the history, purpose and structure of the union, a speech for the Store Chairman's' Dinner talking about organizing 1199, and a report to the Executive Board regarding current union issues.
- Leon J. Davis-Reports, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Contains a report on DPOW National Executive Board discussing the creation of the DPO, a report to 1199 Drug News regarding the content of the newsletter, a report on the reorganization of the divisions of 1199, a report to Convention of Distributive Workers Union regarding challenges of the union, an introductory report on "the state of the union" regarding the struggles of 1199, a report to Liggett and Whelan Steward Conference regarding the purpose of unions, and a report commenting on Negro History Week regarding race relations in the U.S.
- Leon J. Davis-Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Contains reports on "the state of the union" regarding past and current 1199 activities, a speech for the National Pharmaceutical Convention regarding the current situation for workers in the pharmaceutical industry, a report to the DPO Convention current 1199 activities, a report on the Organizational Drive for 40-5 discussing the prospects of a forty hour five days a week work schedule, and a report to Officers' Meeting DPO.
- Leon J. Davis-Seminars, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Contains a pamphlet of the American Assembly-Columbia University's Report on Black Economic Development. Contains correspondence with Columbia University regarding Davis' appointment as Associate in the University Seminar on Labor. Contains correspondence with individuals regarding the seminar and contains a participants guide to the seminar. Also contains a participants' book entitled "Challenges to Collective Bargaining."
- Leon J. Davis-Speech, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Contains an outline of a statement, and the actual statement written by Davis and presented to the Permanent Administrative Committee regarding union policies.
- Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc., 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with publications, unions, religious groups, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government departments, lawyers, hospitals and colleges and universities regarding invitations to events or conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist, receiving awards, invitations for membership, and requests for interviews. Also contains a brochure, Davis' tax filings, a transcript of one of his speeches, a flyer, a formal invitation, and telegrams.
- Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc., 1968-1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with publications, unions, religious groups, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government departments, the house of representatives, a radio station and television station, lawyers, hospitals, colleges and universities, A. Philip Randolph, and Ted Kheel regarding invitations to events and conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist, receiving awards, invitations for membership, elections and requests for interviews. Also contains a copy of an article written by Davis, form letters, an event program, a transcript of a Davis' televised debate, and proposal for a new college from CUNY.
- Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc., 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with unions, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government officials, lawyers, hospitals, colleges and universities, regarding invitations to events and conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist and requests for interviews. Also contains a newspaper article and an outline for a book on labor.
- Leon J. Davis-State of the Union Message, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Contains a copy of Davis' State of the Union Message entitled "Where is 1199 now?" Also contains a summary of the State of the Union Message.
- Leon J. Davis-State of the Union Report, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Contains a copy of the Summary of President Davis' State of the Union Message, "Where is 1199 now?"
- Leon J. Davis- Statement to Congressional Committee, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Contains a copy of a statement submitted by Davis to the Congressional Committee regarding working conditions in voluntary hospitals.
- Leon J. Davis Testimonial Dinner, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Contains memorandums, remarks by Davis at the testimonial dinner, a copy of the actual dinner invitation, lists of reservations, seating lists, remarks by William Michelson at the testimonial dinner, correspondence with people invited to the dinner and with the organizers of the dinner, the financial report for the dinner, ticket forms, list of contributors, telegrams, ledger of dinner donations and tickets sold, a dinner tally, and a brochure.
- Drug Industry Petitions to Wage Board, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence with various drug and pharmaceutical companies informing them that 1199 is going on strike. Contains correspondence with lawyers. Contains correspondence between the Pay Board and the drug and pharmaceutical companies.
- Drug and Hospital News, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Contains typed up copies of articles from the 1199 Drug and Hospital News.
- Election Board [folder 1 of 3], 1970 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence regarding opening a post office box for the election board. Contains an election summary, 1199 election guide with pictures of candidates, a memo from the committee on political education, copy of election issue of 1199 Drug and Hospital News, election schedule, election ballot, election flyer, oath for new 1199 officers, election board meeting minutes, and an election board report.
- Election Board [folder 2 of 3], 1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Contains an election board report, election board meeting minutes, election ballots, a brochure for election consultants, list of voting locations, election schedule, election summary, a from letter with election details, memo to all area directors from election board containing election instructions, voting machine directions, voting machine locations, 1199 election guide with pictures of candidates, copy of election issue of 1199 Drug and Hospital News, election flyers, election facts sheet, list of election materials needed, nominating petitions, reimbursement forms for lost wages during election voting, monthly wage report, and first election board meeting agenda.
- Election Board [folder 3 of 3], 1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Contains nominating petitions, local 1199 delegates election reports, list of election deputies, delegate voting schedules and petitions, election summaries, election tally sheets, election ballots, 1199 election guide, official delegate nominating petition, election flyers and signs, memorandums, election fact sheets, secret ballots, voting machine directions, materials needed for election, election board members, and an attendance list.
- Elections, 1952-1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Contains election board report, membership composition report, form letter sent to members reminding them to vote, sample ballot, election board meeting minutes, correspondence between Davis and the election board, voting advertisements, a notice to vote, election summary, election campaign statistics, 1972 elected delegates, correspondence with various community leaders regarding elections, and reports to delegates assemblies.
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1953-1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Contains local 1199 benefit plan brochure, local 1199 benefit plan annual claim experience report, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, a memorandum regarding benefits, 1199 benefit plan resolution, local 1199 benefit plan statement of financial condition, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan pension fund administrative budget, benefit plan director's annual report, and local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations.
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Contains local 1199 benefit plan brochure, benefit plan director's annual report, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, letter from accountants to benefit plan, local 1199 benefit plan statement of financial condition, and local 1199 benefit plan report of the Amalgamated Bank of New York.
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Contain dental program and prescription program brochure, the local 1199 benefit plan brochure, an agreement and declaration of trust, local 1199 benefit plan report of the Amalgamated Bank of New York, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations amendment, hospital listing for claims department, the local 1199 benefit plan, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, schedule of benefit plan members, and schedule of telephone charges. Also contains correspondence with lawyers and others regarding meetings, and alterations to the benefit plan.
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- 1199 Benefit Plan, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Contains local 1199 benefit plan financial report.
- 1199 Credit Union, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Contains a report on the credit union.
- 1199 News, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Contains several rough drafts of articles for the 1199 News.
- 1199 Pension Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Contains local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, and local 1199 pension fund pension plan study.
- 1199 Pension Plan, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Contains memo regarding local 1199 pension fund trustees, secretary-treasurer's annual report, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment account, local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, State of New York Insurance Department report on examination of local 1199 Pension Fund, local 1199 pension fund annual report, and local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition.
- 1199 Pension Plan, 1965-1975 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Contains local 1199 pension fund outline of principal provisions, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment account, local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension plan brochure, secretary-treasurer's annual report, a letter and financial records from accountants, and local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition.
- 1199 Pension Fund, 1951-1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)